<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en">

  <!-- Begin Jekyll SEO tag v2.3.0 -->
<title>Feed | Early Spring Excursion</title>
<meta property="og:title" content="Feed" />
<meta name="author" content="Luche & Johanna" />
<meta property="og:locale" content="en_US" />
<meta name="description" content="Your Mysterious China Tour" />
<meta property="og:description" content="Your Mysterious China Tour" />
<link rel="canonical" href="http://earlyspringexcursion.com/cn/feed.xml" />
<meta property="og:url" content="http://earlyspringexcursion.com/feed.xml" />
<meta property="og:site_name" content="Early Spring Excursion" />
<script type="application/ld+json">
{"name":null,"description":"Your Mysterious China Tour","author":{"@type":"Person","name":"Luche & Johanna"},"@type":"WebPage","url":"http://earlyspringexcursion.com/feed.xml","publisher":null,"image":null,"headline":"Feed","dateModified":null,"datePublished":null,"sameAs":null,"mainEntityOfPage":null,"@context":"http://schema.org"}</script>
<!-- End Jekyll SEO tag -->

<head>
    <meta charset="utf-8">
    <meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="IE=edge">
    <title>Feed</title>
    <meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1,maximum-scale=1, user-scalable=no">
    <meta name="description" content="Your Mysterious China Tour">
    <link rel="canonical" href="http://earlyspringexcursion.com/cn/feed.xml">

    <!-- Custom CSS -->
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/main.css">
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/pygments.css">
</head>


    <body>

      <div class="container">

                <div class="header">
    <p>
        <img src=/images/logo.png>
    </p>

			</div>

    <div class="nav">
        <ul>
            
            <li class="current"><a href="/cn/index.html">Home</a></li>

				<li> <a href="/cn/stories">Stories</a></li>

				<li> <a href="/cn/china-tours">Tours</a></li>

            <li> <a href="/cn/get-in-touch">Get in Touch</a></li>
            
        </ul>
    </div>
<div class="lang">

<a href="/cn/"><img  src=/images/uk.png></img></a>
<a href="/cn/fr"><img  src=/images/france.png></img></a>
<a href="/cn/cn"><img href="/cn/cn" src=/images/china.png></img></a>

</div>

        <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Early Spring Excursion</title>
    <description>Your Mysterious China Tour</description>
    <link>http://earlyspringexcursion.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://earlyspringexcursion.com/cn/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Why having a good tour guide in China so useful is&amp;#8230;</title>
        <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  My happiest memories while traveling are definitely meeting local people and sharing a part of their daily life. Living the beauty of diversity. I have been to many different countries around Asia, Europe and Africa, but one of those countries that is not easy to travel is China. Here I want to share you three important reasons why having a good guide can transform your experience in China.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-a-good-guide-is-also-your-translator-and-beyond-translations-a-communication-facilitator&quot;&gt;1-A good guide is also your translator and beyond translations, a communication facilitator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Communication is the first barrier between the traveler and the local people. While living in China, I bumped into many travelers who do not speak chinese and understand chinese culture. Their journey in China was sometimes a headache from booking train tickets, chatting with a curious neighbor on the bus or ordering a nice food in a restaurant &amp;#8230; Many places to not have English  and just see characters everywhere.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-a-good-guide-will-not-take-you-in-those-touristy-areas&quot;&gt;2-A good guide will not take you in those touristy areas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Famous places or those offered in travels agencies are double faced. The fast development of tourism in China completely can change a place into something else within half a year of time. And speaking about tourism, it is often transformed into something not so pleasant.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Bus of tourists along the streets, very loud karaoke style music all over the village, souvenirs shops&amp;#8230; After you have been to a couple of touristic areas in China, you might wish not go to those kind of artificial places again&amp;#8230;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3--a-good-guide-will-show-you-deep-hidden-places-that-you-wont-find-on-internet&quot;&gt;3- A good guide will show you deep hidden places that you won’t find on internet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
  Traveling in China can be frustrating not only for foreigner or well-traveled people but even for Chinese who are looking for getting off the beaten tracks. That needs a lot of time and energy to find places not many people talk about!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of that makes traveling in China so interesting, unique and kind of charming too. China has still so many wonderful aspects to show us. It is just about how you look at it! That’s why we would like to guide travelers through the mysteries of Chinese life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you will getting to understand better and better, in China, everything is about having the right key to open you the right door for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 12:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://earlyspringexcursion.com/tour-guide-china-useful/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://earlyspringexcursion.com/tour-guide-china-useful/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wild food around Yunnan&amp;#8217;s mountains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We just came back from a couple of days on a small house on the mountains between Dali and Lijiang. A old couple of farmers is living there with their grand daughter and her parents come to visit once a week. That is how we came here with the parents who are running a chinese medicinal herbs shop in our town. The family is from the Bai minority, the major minority here in Dali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about-mountain-food&quot;&gt;About mountain food&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;oil-tea-for-breakfast&quot;&gt;Oil tea for breakfast&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we all woke up, the grandpa started to prepare their traditional breakfast: youcha (oil tea) and baba (bread)… The oil tea is a drink that keep the body warm and full of energy during the day in the mountains. It is made out of pork fat in which rice is added and fried. Then we add water, salt and tea leaves in the pot and boil it on the fire for about half an hour. The result is a strong, very oily, salty and bit bitter drink. I could even find some pieces of pork fat but I assure you, it tastes delicious with the fresh made baba bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pears-apples-and-nuts&quot;&gt;Pears, apples and nuts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stroll around the mountain and found plenty wild pear and walnut trees. That is also a gift from nature while in our markets and supermarkets,  most of the fruits and vegetables are full of pesticides and other chemicals! We started to fill our backpack with all those different types of pears so it could last us for a while back in Dali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;sichuan-pepper&quot;&gt;Sichuan pepper&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The freshly cut bush of Sichuan pepper was filling the air and came to our nose. If you never hear about Sichuan pepper, it is a commonly used spice in Chinese cuisine, it tastes totally strange the first time you eat it and numb your mouth.  During the past years, the more I got to eat it the more I liked it. We had fun taking these small berries from the bush and filled another small bag of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;honey&quot;&gt;Honey&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honey bees were busy going in and out of their hive located in the clay walls. The taste of the pure honey with the comb and pollen is absolutely delicious. It is particularly rare to find pure honey since most of the bees in China are fed with sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hosts’s first son invited us to have lunch not on the other side of the mountain. The oil tea from breakfast was not finished to digest, we already had lunch. His wife had prepared a chicken for our coming. Wow it is always touching how some people in the countryside treat their guests by offering them the best of what they have…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about-life-on-the-mountain&quot;&gt;About life on the mountain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is quite hard up their. The town is about one hour road away, a difficult road full of curves and holes. So the people living here have created a quite autonomous way of life and that is what I think is the most interesting by coming here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;water&quot;&gt;Water&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also was pretty amazed with their water system. They use rainwater from the roof they store in an underground container made of cement. It was the second time in my life I have seen this water system. The first time was in France in the first fully autonomous house called La Maison Autonome in Chateaubriand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have already describe some stuff about food above, I will just add some details. Each family grows vegetables and breeds pigs for their meat and fat (maybe the fat is even more important than meat.) They also have chickens (also here, more for the meat than for their eggs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mountain is full of wild plants, nuts and mushrooms. On the way back home, we just bumped into two women who were coming back from their truffle “hunting” and our friend, a real businesss man type, just bought every single one for a pretty good price…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;energy&quot;&gt;Energy&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen many houses using sun heated water system and solar panels since here in Yunnan, sun is quite an infinite ressource. Otherwise, most of the electricity comes from nearby hydroelectric plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I think that’s for it now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you have learned something 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johanna&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 11:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://earlyspringexcursion.com/wandering-wonders-yunnan-mountains/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://earlyspringexcursion.com/wandering-wonders-yunnan-mountains/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


                <footer class="site-footer">
<img src="/images/seal.png"></img><br/>
<a href="/cn/about-this-site">About this site</a><br/>
<a href="/cn/about-us">About us</a><br/>
<ul" >Luche & Johanna</ul>
</footer>

      </div>

    </body>
</html>
